# Christopher Lehneis

EMAIL: cdlehneis@gmail.com

PHONE: 631.252.8117

GITHUB: github.com/SyntaxChris



#### **PROFILE**

Full Stack Web Developer with an object oriented programming background in Ruby and Javascript. Demonstrated team player in an Agile software environment with a passion for expressing creativity with the latest web technologies. Prior knowledge in automated manufacturing, robotics, electronics, prosthetics and orthotics. Served over five years in the United States Coast Guard as an Electronics Technician leading and supervising installation upgrade teams throughout the United States.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Full Stack Web Developer, Dopamine Inc., New York, NY

8/2014-Present

- Develops web applications using Javascript (Angular JS, ¡Query), Ruby (Ruby on Rails), CSS3 (SASS), and HTML5 with an Agile software team.
- Sets up Linux server environments and deploys applications into production utilizing NGINX and load balancers.
- Built the front end of a gamified survey application for LAX airport (CSS3, Angular.js, ¡Query) beatLAXtraffic.com

## Training Coordinator, Learn CNC Machining Inc., Bohemia, NY 8/2013-4/2014

- Developed, and taught curriculums for Computer Numerical Controller (CNC) programing, and Computer Aided Design (CAD) software, and setup/operator training classes.
- Designed marketing material for featured software training programs.
- Provided customer support for troubleshooting CAD software.

## Field Service Engineer, Automation Solutions Inc., West Chester, PA 5/2012-3/2013

- Installed, serviced and programmed CNC machining centers for automated manufacturing at over 30 manufacturing companies on the east coast of the United States.
- Developed machine damage assessment caused by the flood aftermath of hurricane Sandy, resulting in a refurbishing cost savings of 25% at Triumph Actuation systems, Freeport Ny.
- Implemented FANUC robotic servo arm systems for large scale automotive manufacturing companies.

# Christopher Lehneis

#### Orthotics Technician, Lehneis O & P Associates Ltd., Roslyn, NY 4/2008-12/2011

- Designed, fabricated, and fitted orthotic and prosthetic devices for patients.
- Integrated CAD software in orthotic and prosthetic designs.
- Managed inventory for all orthotic and prosthetic products and supplies.

## Electronics Technician, United States Coast Guard, Cape May, NJ 2/2003-3/2008

- Lead Electronics Technician that provided leadership and management for teams teams that upgraded over 30 Long Range Aids To Navigation (LORAN) stations throughout the United States.
- Qualified officer of the day, responsible for all unit operations and security including hotline watch stander qualification to provide assistance to all U.S. and Canadian Loran stations
- Active Search and Rescue Boat-crew member and Received Coast Guard special operations service ribbon for diligent security operations during the 2004 Americas Cup in Newport Harbor.

#### **EDUCATION**

## The Flatiron School, Web Development Fellowship

8/2014

12 week Web Development Immersive program + 12 week internship Science fair project - challengepost.com/software/morse-bot

#### State University of New York at Stony Brook

5/2012

Bachelors of Applied Science, Technological Systems Management

## Thomas Edison State University

5/2008

Associates of Applied Science, Electronics Studies

#### **SKILLS**

Ruby	Ruby on Rails	Javascript	įQuery
Angular.js	CSS3	SASS	HTML 5
Zurb Foundation	Bootstrap	Postgresql	Command Line
Git/Github	Linux	Agile Development	Adobe Illustrator
Adobe Photoshop	Arduino	Raspberry pi	Electronics